Juan E. Velasquez T. Project Engineer

Personal Info

Eindhoven, The Netherlands

<u>juanovelas quez 10@gmail.com</u>

+31 0658794668

Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/juanevelasquezt/

Skills

Project Management

Advance

Data Analysis

Intermediate

Report writting

Expert

Teamwork

Expert

Communication

Expert

Leadership

Intermediate

Problem-Solving

Advance

Software

Microsoft Office

Advance

AutoCAD

Advance

Tekla 3D

Advance

Python

Intermediate

MEPLA

Intemediate

Languages

Spanish

Native

English

Fluent

Portuguese

Beginner

Project engineer with a background in sophisticated construction products, project management and green buildings. 3+ years of professional experience working with multidisciplinary and international teams. Qualified with the essential knowledge and expertise to manage international teams, understand complex engineering subjects and terminology, and thrive in a fast paced environment.

Education

The University of Manchester

Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

Sep 2014 – Jun 2018

MSc in Management

- Dissertation distinction in corporate financial evaluation
- · Treasurer of the Latin American Society

Cardiff University

BEng (Hons) Architectural Engineering

- Full Sketch-Up airport model
- Founder of the Latin American Society
- Architectural Engineering 1st year representative

Work Experience

Byldis B.V. (NL) – 3D Engineer

Feb 2022 – present

- Solely managing the 3D modeling of a 15 story building, and supervise another colleague over the preparation of the production drawings
- Lead sales engineer for the Overkoeks Block N project in Amsterdam. Calculated and converted
 the clients building specifications into prefabricated building elements to be easily produced and
 efficiently installed on site.
- Developed BIM integrated model to improve coordination between structural engineers, MEP engineers, architects and other relevant stakeholders.
- Experience in using BIM tools, such as Autodesk BIM360, to optimize the flow of information between different project stakeholders and achieve established goals more efficiently.

eyrise B.V. (NL) – Project Engineer

Mar 2020 – Feb 2022

- Solely researched and built the solar and privacy product's green certification labels (LEED)
 documentation and worked closely with external consultants for the development of the
 Environmental Product Declaration (EPD).
- Project engineer for the German Campus dynamic glazing façade (Dubai EXPO 2020), with a focus
 on improving the product to make it viable for sustaining high temperatures. This improvement
 increased the products exposure globally, making it adaptable to endure all types of weather.
- Project leader for the official eyrise i350 privacy product launch cubicle in Darmstadt, Germany.
 Calculated and remodeled the products functionality and technical aspects, whilst also supervising the supply chain in order to meet the tight deadlines.
- Provided sales engineering and quality support for the Amazon MK3 façade in Munich, Germany. This included delivering and showcasing the product mockup vs the competitors mockup, and solve unitized façade adaptations that contributed to eyrise winning the project in 2021.

Certifications

Apix Development	Feb 2022
Tekla 3D structures basis Edx — DelftX	Nov 2021
Buildings as sustainable energy systems (Professional certification) Coursera — Duke University	Aug 2020
Renewable Energy and Green Building Entrepreneurship	J
Coursera – The State University of New Solar Energy Basics	Aug 2019
Green Building Certification Inc.	Dec 2019

Additional Information

LEED Green Associate

Volunteering: Encourage and help to host charity events in Cardiff to raise money for the victims of the natural disasters in Colombia and Mexico. Recollect funds in Manchester for a Guatemalan NGO, Entremundos.

Interests: cooking, football, ultimate frisbee, Manchester United and reading.